Osborne Family Papers
Osborne Family Papers
New York State; Politics, government and public administration; Activism and social reform; Civil War (U.S.); Daniels, Josephus, 1862-1948.; Devens, Charles, 1820-1891.; Herter, Christian Archibald, 1895-1966.; Howe, Louis M. (Louis McHenry), 1871-1936.; Lehman, Herbert H. (Herbert Henry), 1878-1963.; Mott, Lucretia, 1793-1880.; Osborne, David Munson, 1822-1886.; Osborne, Lithgow, 1892-1980.; Osborne, Thomas Mott, 1859-1926.; Osborne family.; Osborne family -- Genealogy.; Peabody, George Foster, 1852-1938.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945.; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962.; Smith, Alfred Emanuel, 1873-1944.; Trask, Katrina, 1853-1922.; Villard, Oswald Garrison, 1872-1949.; Wright, Martha Coffin, 1806-1875.; Wright, David Minton, 1809-1863.; George Junior Republic (Freeville, N.Y.); Democratic Party (N.Y.); Capital punishment.; Genealogy.; Philanthropists -- United States.; Prison reformers -- United States.; Prison wardens -- New York (State); Prisoners -- Legal status, laws, etc. -- New York (State); Social reformers -- United States.; Suffragists -- United States.; Upper class -- United States.; Women's rights.; Auburn, N.Y. -- History.; Cayuga County (N.Y.) -- Social life and customs.; New York (State) -- History.; New York (State) -- Officials and employees.; New York (State) -- Politics and government.; United States -- Foreign relations -- 1913-1921.; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.; United States -- Politics and government -- 20th century.; Account books.; Correspondence.; Diaries.; Financial records.; Letter books.; Photographs.; Speeches (documents); Prison reformers.; Social reformers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Material relating to W. R. George restricted until 2020 at the request of Lithgow Osborne.
Inventory
- Communications and writings
  - Correspondence
    - Chronological order
      - 1812 Gen - 1823 Jun (Box 1)
      - 1823 Jul - 1838 Apr (Box 2)
      - 1838 May - 1841 Mar (Box 3)
      - 1841 Apr - 1843 Nov (Box 4)
      - 1843 Dec - 1846 Oct (Box 5)
      - 1846 Nov - 1849 Jul (Box 6)
      - 1849 Aug - 1852 Dec (Box 7)
      - 1853 Gen - 1856 Dec (Box 8)
      - 1857 Gen - 1858 Nov (Box 9)
      - 1858 Dec - 1862 Jul (Box 10)
      - 1862 Aug - 1866 Jan (Box 11)
      - 1866 Feb - 1869 Jun (Box 12)
      - 1869 Jul - 1872 Mar (Box 13)
      - 1872 Apr - 1875 Nov (Box 14)
      - 1875 Dec - 1877 Jun (Box 15)
      - 1877 Jul - 1878 Oct (Box 16)
      - 1878 Nov - 1879 Nov (Box 17)
      - 1879 Dec - 1881 Feb (Box 18)
      - 1881 Mar - 1882 Apr (Box 19)
      - 1882 May - 1883 Oct (Box 20)
      - 1883 Nov - 1884 Oct (Box 21)
      - 1884 Nov - 1885 Jun (Box 22)
      - 1885 Jul - 1886 Jan (Box 23)
      - 1886 Feb - 1886 Jul (Box 24)
      - 1886 Aug - 1887 Mar (Box 25)
      - 1887 Apr - 1887 Dec (Box 26)
      - 1888 Gen - 1888 Sep (Box 27)
      - 1888 Oct - 1889 Jul (Box 28)
      - 1889 Aug - 1890 Mar (Box 29)
      - 1890 Apr - 1891 Gen (Box 30)
      - 1891 Jan - 1891 Nov (Box 31)
      - 1891 Dec - 1892 Aug (Box 32)
      - 1892 Sep - 1893 Sep (Box 33)
      - 1893 Oct - 1894 Sep (Box 34)
      - 1894 Oct - 1896 Jan (Box 35)
      - 1896 Feb - 1896 Oct (Box 36)
      - 1896 Nov - 1897 Oct (Box 37)
      - 1897 Nov - 1898 Jul (Box 38)
      - 1898 Aug - 1899 Jun (Box 39)
      - 1899 Jul - 1900 Jan (Box 40)
      - 1900 Feb - 1900 May (Box 41)
      - 1900 Jun - 1900 Sep (Box 42)
      - 1900 Oct - 1901 Jan (Box 43)
      - 1901 Feb - 1901 Apr (Box 44)
      - 1901 May - 1901 Jul (Box 45)
      - 1901 Aug - 1901 Dec (Box 46)
      - 1902 Gen - 1902 Apr (Box 47)
      - 1902 May - 1902 Sep (Box 48)
      - 1902 Oct - 1902 Dec (Box 49)
      - 1903 Gen - 1903 Mar (Box 50)
      - 1903 Apr - 1903 Jun (Box 51)
      - 1903 Jul - 1904 Gen (Box 52)
      - 1904 Feb - 1904 Apr (Box 53)
      - 1904 Apr - 1904 Aug (Box 54)
      - 1904 Aug - 1905 Feb (Box 55)
      - 1905 Feb - 1905 May (Box 56)
      - 1905 May - 1905 Nov (Box 57)
      - 1905 Nov - 1906 Jan (Box 58)
      - 1906 Feb - 1906 Apr (Box 59)
      - 1906 May - 1906 Jul (Box 60)
      - 1906 Jul - 1906 Oct (Box 61)
      - 1906 Oct - 1906 Nov (Box 62)
      - 1906 Dec - 1907 Feb (Box 63)
      - 1907 Feb - 1907 Apr (Box 64)
      - 1907 May - 1907 Jun (Box 65)
      - 1907 Jul - 1907 Oct (Box 66)
      - 1907 Oct - 1907 Dec (Box 67)
      - 1908 Gen - 1908 Feb (Box 68)
      - 1908 Feb - 1908 Apr (Box 69)
      - 1908 Apr - 1908 Jun (Box 70)
      - 1908 Jun - 1908 Aug (Box 71)
      - 1908 Aug - 1908 Oct (Box 72)
      - 1908 Nov - 1909 Gen (Box 73)
      - 1909 Jan - 1909 Feb (Box 74)
      - 1909 Mar - 1909 Apr (Box 75)
      - 1909 May - 1909 Jul (Box 76)
      - 1909 Jul - 1909 Oct (Box 77)
      - 1909 Oct - 1909 Nov (Box 78)
      - 1909 Dec - 1910 Jan (Box 79)
      - 1910 Jan - 1910 Mar (Box 80)
      - 1910 Mar - 1910 May (Box 81)
      - 1910 May - 1910 Jul (Box 82)
      - 1910 Jul - 1910 Aug (Box 83)
      - 1910 Aug - 1910 Oct (Box 84)
      - 1910 Oct - 1910 Dec (Box 85)
      - 1910 Dec - 1911 Jan (Box 86)
      - 1911 Feb - 1911 Mar (Box 87)
      - 1911 Mar - 1911 Apr (Box 88)
      - 1911 May - 1911 Jul (Box 89)
      - 1911 Jul - 1911 Oct (Box 90)
      - 1911 Oct - 1911 Dec (Box 91)
      - 1912 Gen - 1912 Feb (Box 92)
      - 1912 Feb - 1912 Apr (Box 93)
      - 1912 May - 1912 Jul (Box 94)
      - 1912 Jul - 1912 Sep (Box 95)
      - 1912 Sep - 1912 Dec (Box 96)
      - 1912 Dec - 1913 Feb (Box 97)
      - 1913 Mar - 1913 May (Box 98)
      - 1913 Jun - 1913 Aug (Box 99)
      - 1913 Aug - 1913 Oct (Box 100)
      - 1913 Oct - 1913 Dec (Box 101)
      - 1913 Dec - 1914 Feb (Box 102)
      - 1914 Feb - 1914 Apr (Box 103)
      - 1914 Apr - 1914 Jun (Box 104)
      - 1914 Jun - 1914 Aug (Box 105)
      - 1914 Aug - 1914 Oct (Box 106)
      - 1914 Oct - 1914 Nov (Box 107)
      - 1914 Dec (Box 108)
      - 1914 Dec - 1915 Jan (Box 109)
      - 1915 Jan - 1915 Feb (Box 110)
      - 1915 Feb - 1915 Mar (Box 111)
      - 1915 Mar - 1915 Apr (Box 112)
      - 1915 Apr - 1915 May (Box 113)
      - 1915 May - 1915 Jun (Box 114)
      - 1915 Jun - 1915 Jul (Box 115)
      - 1915 Jul (Box 116)
      - 1915 Aug (Box 117)
      - 1915 Aug - 1915 Sep (Box 118)
      - 1915 Sep - 1915 Oct (Box 119)
      - 1915 Oct - 1915 Nov (Box 120)
      - 1915 Nov - 1915 Dec (Box 121)
      - 1915 Dec - 1916 Gen (Box 122)
      - 1916 Jan (Box 123)
      - 1916 Feb - 1916 Mar (Box 124)
      - 1916 Mar - 1916 Apr (Box 125)
      - 1916 May - 1916 Jun (Box 126)
      - 1916 Jun - 1916 Jul (Box 127)
      - 1916 Jul - 1916 Aug (Box 128)
      - 1916 Sep - 1916 Oct (Box 129)
      - 1916 Oct - 1916 Nov (Box 130)
      - 1916 Nov - 1916 Dec (Box 131)
      - 1916 Dec - 1917 Jan (Box 132)
      - 1917 Jan - 1917 Mar (Box 133)
      - 1917 Mar - 1917 May (Box 134)
      - 1917 May - 1917 Jul (Box 135)
      - 1917 Jul - 1917 Aug (Box 136)
      - 1917 Sep - 1917 Oct (Box 137)
      - 1917 Oct - 1917 Nov (Box 138)
      - 1917 Nov - 1918 Gen (Box 139)
      - 1918 Jan - 1918 Feb (Box 140)
      - 1918 Mar - 1918 Apr (Box 141)
      - 1918 May - 1918 Jun (Box 142)
      - 1918 Jul - 1918 Aug (Box 143)
      - 1918 Sep - 1918 Nov (Box 144)
      - 1918 Nov - 1919 Jan (Box 145)
      - 1919 Jan - 1919 Mar (Box 146)
      - 1919 Mar - 1919 May (Box 147)
      - 1919 May - 1919 Jul (Box 148)
      - 1919 Aug - 1919 Sep (Box 149)
      - 1919 Oct - 1919 Nov (Box 150)
      - 1919 Nov - 1920 Gen (Box 151)
      - 1920 Jan - 1920 Feb (Box 152)
      - 1920 Mar - 1920 May (Box 153)
      - 1920 Jun - 1920 Aug (Box 154)
      - 1920 Aug - 1920 Oct (Box 155)
      - 1920 Nov - 1921 Jan (Box 156)
      - 1921 Jan - 1921 Apr (Box 157)
      - 1921 May - 1921 Aug (Box 158)
      - 1921 Aug - 1921 Nov (Box 159)
      - 1921 Nov - 1922 Feb (Box 160)
      - 1922 Feb - 1922 Apr (Box 161)
      - 1922 May - 1922 Sep (Box 162)
      - 1922 Oct - 1923 Jan (Box 163)
      - 1923 Feb - 1923 May (Box 164)
      - 1923 May - 1923 Aug (Box 165)
      - 1923 Aug - 1923 Nov (Box 166)
      - 1923 Nov - 1924 Feb (Box 167)
      - 1924 Feb - 1924 May (Box 168)
      - 1924 May - 1924 Aug (Box 169)
      - 1924 Sep - 1924 Oct (Box 170)
      - 1924 Oct - 1925 Jan (Box 171)
      - 1925 Jan - 1925 Apr (Box 172)
      - 1925 Apr - 1925 Jul (Box 173)
      - 1925 Aug - 1925 Oct (Box 174)
      - 1925 Nov - 1926 Jan (Box 175)
      - 1926 Feb - 1926 Jul (Box 176)
      - 1926 Aug - 1926 Nov (Box 177)
      - 1926 Dec - 1927 Jun (Box 178)
      - 1927 Jul - 1928 Mar (Box 179)
      - 1928 Apr - 1929 May (Box 180)
      - 1929 Jun - 1930 Oct (Box 181)
      - 1930 Nov - 1931 Oct (Box 182)
      - 1931 Nov - 1932 Sep (Box 183)
      - 1932 Oct - 1933 Mar (Box 184)
      - 1933 Mar - 1935 Jul (Box 185)
      - 1935 Aug - 1937 Sep (Box 186)
      - 1937 Oct - 1940 Feb (Box 187)
      - 1940 Mar - 1942 May (Box 188)
      - 1942 Jun - 1943 Sep (Box 189)
      - 1943 Oct - 1944 Aug (Box 190)
      - 1944 Sep - 1945 May (Box 191)
      - 1945 Jun - 1945 Nov (Box 192)
      - 1945 Dec - 1946 Jul (Box 193)
      - 1946 Aug - 1949 Sep (Box 194)
      - 1949 Oct - 1953 Aug (Box 195)
      - 1953 Sep - 1956 Aug (Box 196)
      - 1956 Sep - 1961 Jul (Box 197)
      - 1961 Aug - 1963 Aug (Box 198)
      - 1963 Sep - 1964 Apr (Box 199)
      - 1964 May - 1964 Oct (Box 200)
      - 1964 Nov - 1965 Jul (Box 201)
      - 1965 Jul - 1966 Apr (Box 202)
      - 1966 May - 1966 Nov (Box 203)
      - 1966 Dec - 1967 May (Box 204)
      - 1967 Jun - 1968 Jan (Box 205)
    - Alphabetical order
      - A-O (Box 206)
      - Osborne, Mrs. D. M., few undated postcards; large number of empty envelopes (Box 206)
      - Osborne, Thomas Mott (Box 206)
      - Osborne Family, general (Box 206)
      - P, R-S (Box 206)
      - Storrow, Helen (Osborne) (Box 206)
      - T-U (Box 206)
      - V-W (Box 207)
      - Wright, Martha (Coffin) (Box 207)
      - Y- Z (Box 207)
      - Unidentified (Box 207)
    - Letter books, Thomas Mott Osborne
      - General correspondence
        - 1892 May - 1895 Aug (Vol. 1) (Box 208)
        - 1895 Aug - 1896 Jul (Vol. 2) (Box 209)
        - 1896 Jul - 1898 Jan (Vol. 3) (Box 210)
        - 1898 Jan - 1899 Jan (Vol. 4) (Box 211)
        - 1899 Jan - 1900 Jan (Vol. 5) (Box 212)
        - 1900 Jan - 1900 Sep (Vol. 6) (Box 213)
        - 1900 Sep - 1901 May (Vol. 7) (Box 214)
        - 1901 May - 1902 Feb (Vol. 8) (Box 215)
        - 1902 Feb - 1902 Oct (Vol. 9) (Box 216)
        - 1902 Oct - 1903 Apr (Vol. 10) (Box 217)
        - 1903 Apr - 1903 Dec (Vol. 11) (Box 218)
        - 1903 Dec - 1904 Aug (Vol. 12) (Box 219)
        - 1904 Aug - 1905 May (Vol. 13) (Box 220)
        - 1905 May - 1906 Jan (Vol. 14) (Box 221)
        - 1906 Jan - 1906 Feb (Vol. 15) (Box 222)
      - George Junior Republic
        - 1898 Jan - 1899 Apr (Vol. 16) (Box 223)
        - 1899 Apr - 1900 May (Vol. 17) (Box 224)
        - 1900 May - 1901 Jan (Vol. 18) (Box 225)
    - Transcriptions, Will David on world tour, 1877 Sep 17 - 1877 Oct 23; 1877 Oct 26 - 1878 Jun 9,; 1878 Jun 18 - 1878 Aug 15; 6 folders (Box 226)
  - Speeches
    - Anonymous and miscellaneous, 1906-1938 (Box 227)
    - Adler, Mortimer / On Thomas Mott Osborne, undated (Box 227)
    - Battle, George Gordon / On Thomas Mott Osborne, 1915 (Box 227)
    - Devens, Charles / On Patriotism, 1887-1890; printed material (Box 227)
    - Dix, John A. / On State Finance, 1915 (Box 227)
    - Doty, Madeleine Zabriskie / On Prisons and Reformatories, 1915 (Box 227)
    - Drummond, R.S. / Nominating Thomas Mott Osborne, undated (Box 227)
    - Eliot, Samuel A. / On Thomas Mott Osborne, 1927 (Box 227)
    - Harllee, William C., Major, U.S. Marines / On Discipline and Organization, circa 1920 (Box 227)
    - Johnson, Grove Lawrence / On William Randolph Hearst and the Central Pacific Railroad, 1897 (Box 227)
    - Karlin, Alexander / "Crimes and Criminals", 1915 (Box 227)
    - Kirchwey, George W. / On Thomas Mott Osborne, 1927 (Box 227)
    - Kirchwey, George W. and others / On Thomas Mott Osborne, 1927 (Box 227)
    - McCormick, Austin H. / On the Rehabilitation of Criminals, 1935 (Box 227)
    - Mathews, Sylvester J. / "Jacob Leonard", 1902 (Box 227)
    - Osborne, David Munson / "Devonshire Tale", undated (Box 227)
    - Osborne, Lithgow
      - Miscellaneous, 1934-1939 (Box 227)
      - "The American-Friends of Danish Freedom", 1941 (Box 227)
      - "The American-Legion Convention", 1936 (Box 227)
      - "An American Point of View", circa 1945 (Box 227)
      - "American-Norwegian Trade Relations", 1946 (Box 227)
      - "Atlantic Union Practical Politics", circa 1967 (Box 227)
      - On the Auburn Kiwanis Club, circa 1926 (Box 227)
      - On Boy Scouts, circa 1930 (Box 227)
      - On British-American Defenses, 1940 (Box 227)
      - "The Bureau of State Publicity", 1935-1940 (Box 227)
      - On the Civilian Conservation Corps (CCC), 1933-1935 (Box 227)
      - On the Cold War, 1946 (Box 227)
      - Commencement Address, circa 1928 (Box 227)
      - On Campaign Issues, 1923-1942; 5 folders (Box 227)
      - "Confessions of a Ham Actor", 1932 (Box 228)
      - On Conservation, 1934-1942; 3 folders (Box 228)
      - "The Conservation Department and the Public", 1933 (Box 228)
      - On the Conservation Fund, 1939-1940 (Box 228)
      - On Conservation Department Policies, 1939-1940; 3 folders (Box 228)
      - "Conservation Education in the State Conservation Department", 1937 (Box 228)
      - "Crime and Community", 1953 (Box 228)
      - On Criminals and Prisons, 1930 (Box 228)
      - Dedications, 1934 (Box 228)
      - On the Economy, 1932 (Box 228)
      - "English and American Debts", 1932 (Box 228)
      - On Farm Problems, 1933 (Box 228)
      - "The Farmer and Reforestation" (Box 228)
      - "The Farmer-Sportsman Problem", 1935-1938 (Box 228)
      - On Fish and Game, 1933-1942; 3 folders (Box 228)
      - On Forests, 1933-1940 (Box 228)
      - On Historic Sites in New York, 1936 (Box 228)
      - "The Importance of Upstate Democrats", 1932 (Box 228)
      - On the International Situation, 1941-1942 (Box 229)
      - Introduction of Franklin Delano Roosevelt, 1928 (Box 229)
      - On the Lack of Interest in Public Affairs, circa 1928 (Box 229)
      - On the League of Nations, circa 1925 (Box 229)
      - On the Life of Thomas Jefferson, circa 1928 (Box 229)
      - On Mercy Hospital, Auburn, N.Y., circa 1928 (Box 229)
      - On the New York State Conservation Department, 1933-1942 (Box 229)
      - On the New York State Constitutional Convention, 1937-1938 (Box 229)
      - On the New York State Forest Preserve, 1934; 1961 (Box 229)
      - "The New York State Park System", 1934 (Box 229)
      - On the Opening of Conservation Week, 1935 (Box 229)
      - On Patronage, 1955 (Box 229)
      - On Politics, 1933-1940; 2 folders (Box 229)
      - On Pollution, 1941 (Box 229)
      - On Postwar Norway, 1946 (Box 229)
      - On the Presidential Election, 1932; 1948; 2 folders (Box 229)
      - On Prohibition, 1928; 1932; 2 folders (Box 229)
      - On Recreation in New York State, 1936-1941 (Box 229)
      - On the Republican Administration, 1956 (Box 229)
      - "Science and Democracy", circa 1950 (Box 229)
      - "Socialism and Capitalism Compared", circa 1932 (Box 229)
      - In support of F. J. Souhan for Congress, circa 1948 (Box 229)
      - On the Tariff, circa 1928 (Box 229)
      - "The Task of Norwegian Democracy", 1946 (Box 229)
      - On Truck Farming in New York State, 1934 (Box 229)
      - "The United States and Germany, 1914-1917", circa 1932 (Box 229)
      - On the New York State Water Power and Control Commission, 1934-1936 (Box 230)
      - "Where Do Atlanticans Go from Here", circa 1967 (Box 230)
      - On the Wildlife Institution and Biological Survey, 1935; 1936 (Box 230)
      - On Wildlife Management, 1936-1940 (Box 230)
    - Osborne, Thomas Mott
      - Miscellaneous, 1905-1912 (Box 230)
      - "American Ideals", 1921; printed material (Box 230)
      - "The Blight of Politics", 1903 (Box 230)
      - On Business, 1899 (Box 230)
      - On Campaign Issues, 1896-1912; 5 folders (Box 230)
      - On Charles F. Murphy and William Randolph Hearst, 1906 (Box 230)
      - "The Children of the Municipality", circa 1904 (Box 230)
      - "The Civil Service of a Democracy", circa 1910 (Box 230)
      - On Death, 1912 (Box 230)
      - "Democracy and Imperialism", 1908 (Box 230)
      - "Democracy and Progress", circa 1910 (Box 230)
      - "Democracy in Prison Organization", 1920 (Box 230)
      - On the Democratic Party in New York State, 1909 (Box 230)
      - "The Duty of Democrats...", 1896 (Box 230)
      - "Education in a Democracy", circa 1910 (Box 230)
      - On Efficiency and Prisons, 1915 (Box 230)
      - On the George Junior Republic, 1901 (Box 230)
      - On Gothic Architecture, circa 1900 (Box 230)
      - "Governor Roosevelt and the New York Independents", 1898 (Box 231)
      - "Modern Music: Beethoven, Schubert, Wagner", 1900 (Box 231)
      - On the Murphy Ring and Tammany Hall, 1911 (Box 231)
      - On the Mutual Welfare League, 1915 (Box 231)
      - On the National Party, 1900 (Box 231)
      - "A New Theory of Education", 1906 (Box 231)
      - "The Obligations of Woman in a Democracy", 1914 (Box 231)
      - "Our Country", 1906 (Box 231)
      - On Politics, 1903 (Box 231)
      - On the Position of the Independent Democrats in the National Party, 1900 (Box 231)
      - "Politics in Prison Reform", 1920 (Box 231)
      - "Prison Reform", 1915 (Box 231)
      - "For the Prisoner and the State", 1915 (Box 231)
      - On Prisons, 1915 (Box 231)
      - "Progress in the Treatment of the Deficient and Delinquent in the Last Hundred Years", 1925 (Box 231)
      - On Public Utilities, circa 1907 (Box 231)
      - On Reciprocity, 1902 (Box 231)
      - "The Public Service Commission's Law of New York State", circa 1907 (Box 231)
      - On Sing Sing, 1915 (Box 231)
      - On Social Ethics, 1905 (Box 231)
      - "Some Obstacles to Foreign Commerce", circa 1908 (Box 231)
      - "To the Teachers of the Public Schools", 1890 (Box 232)
      - "Training for Municipal Citizenship", 1909 (Box 232)
      - "The True Foundation of Prison Reform", 1906 (Box 232)
      - On Trusts, 1899 (Box 232)
      - "The Waltz", 1900 (Box 232)
      - "War and Democracy", circa 1910 (Box 232)
      - "The War Monument", circa 1919 (Box 232)
      - On Woodrow Wilson, 1912 (Box 232)
    - Robinson, Louis N. / On Prison Labor, 1936 (Box 232)
    - Svaneborg, Kristen / "Scandinavia and America: The War and the Peace Which Will Come", 1915 (Box 232)
    - Sweet, William E.
      - "The Christianization of International Relations", 1924 (Box 232)
      - On Thomas Mott Osborne, 1927 (Box 232)
    - Taber, John / On Campaign Issues, 1942 (Box 232)
    - Tompkins, Arthur S. / On Thomas Mott Osborne, 1915 (Box 232)
    - Wadhams, William H. / On the League of Nations, 1920 (Box 232)
    - Warden, James A. / "Penal Institutions and the Prosecutor", 1916 (Box 232)
    - Wright, David / On Farming in Pennsylvania Around 1820, circa 1885 (Box 232)
  - Writings
    - Miscellaneous, 1910-1920 (Box 232)
    - Anonymous
      - Articles and essays
        - Miscellaneous, 1916-1921 (Box 232)
        - On Thomas Jefferson, circa 1850 (Box 232)
        - "The Siege of Paris", 1870 (Box 232)
      - Books
        - The World's Mystery (fiction), circa 1915; 2 folders (Box 232)
        - Chance (non-fiction), undated (Box 233)
      - Journal, on Charles F. Murphy of Tammany Hall, 1906 (Box 233)
      - Verse, miscellaneous, 1832-1926 (Box 233)
    - Adler, Margaret
      - Article/essay, "Working with Prisoners", circa 1910 (Box 233)
    - Becker, Robert Van
      - Memorial letters on Auburn Prison (Box 233)
    - Bolasky, Harry B.
      - Article/essay, "The Kid Goes Straight", circa 1920 (Box 233)
    - Caponegro, Angelo
      - Article/essay, "How and Where Men are Made Criminals", circa 1915 (Box 233)
    - Chamberlain, Rudolph W.
      - Book, There Is No Truce: A Life of Thomas Mott Osborne, 1935; galley proof (Box 233)
    - Chapman, John Jay
      - Article/essay, "Osborne's Place in Historic Criminology," The Harvard Graduates' Magazine XXXV, 1927 (Box 233)
    - Codding, T.K.
      - Article/essay, "Prison Recreation", 1911 (Box 233)
    - Crane, Frank
      - Article/essay, "Warden Osborne and the System," Los Angeles Express, 1917 (Box 233)
    - Curtis, M.
      - Autobiography, circa 1915 (Box 233)
    - D.T.P.
      - Article/essay, "Third Tickets of the Past", circa 1900 (Box 233)
    - Dalton, Arthur
      - Article/essay, "An Amateur Detective", circa 1915 (Box 233)
    - Dawes, Anna L.
      - Article/essay, "My Impressions of the New Adventure at Sing Sing", 1916 (Box 233)
    - Douglass, Royall
      - Verse, 1911-1913 (Box 233)
    - Dickey, Basil
      - Plays, 1313 and The Gray Brother, 1919 (Box 234)
    - Dutton, Samuel T.
      - Article/essay on Katrina Trask, circa 1910; printed material (Box 234)
    - Eliot, Samuel A.
      - Article/essay, "An Exponent of the Harvard Spirit", 1916 (Box 234)
    - Erskine, John
      - Play, Justice, circa 1915 (Box 234)
    - Farwell, Arthur
      - Play, The Spring of Youth, circa 1911 (Box 234)
      - Verse, "Hymn to Liberty", 1911; printed material (Box 234)
    - Feinberg, Richard
      - Reminiscence on the San Francisco Earthquake and Fire, 1906 (Box 234)
    - Finn, Jonathan and Harold Friedman
      - Film script, Osborne of Sing Sing, 1939 (Box 234)
    - Fever, Charles
      - Article/essay, "To Those Who Doubt", circa 1915 (Box 234)
    - Glueck, Bernard
      - Article/essay, "Types of Delinquent Careers," Mental Hygiene, circa 1915 (Box 234)
    - Goldstein, Jacob
      - Letter to the editor on Thomas Mott Osborne, 1916 (Box 234)
    - Greenan, John
      - Book chapter, "Crime and Its Treatment," American Democracy, Chapter XX, 1923; page proof (Box 234)
    - Harmon, Clifford B.
      - Article/essay, "The Gray City: An Appeal", 1915 (Box 234)
    - Hasty Pudding Club
      - Play and director's notes
        - Ali Baba (Vols. 19-20), 1883 (Box 234)
        - Hernani (Vol. 21), 1884 (Box 234)
    - Jacobs, Israel
      - Diary, 1837 (Box 234)
    - Johnson, Clarence Richard
      - Article/essay, "Prison Facts in Constantinople", circa 1915 (Box 234)
    - Justice, Maibelle Heikes
      - Article/essay, "Who Shall Take My Life?", 1916 (Box 234)
    - Kirchwey, George W.
      - Articles and essays
        - "The Paradox of Occoquan," The Survey, 1921 (Box 234)
        - "What Prisons Do to Men," The Nation, 1922 (Box 234)
    - Lane, Winthrop D.
      - Article/essay, "The Retirement of Thomas Mott Osborne," The Survey, 1916 (Box 234)
      - Obituary, "Thomas Mott Osborne," The Nation, 1926 (Box 234)
    - Lowrie, Donald
      - Articles and essays
        - "Prison Bars," Forum, circa 1915; printed material (Box 234)
        - "The Tom Brown Knitting Class", 1915 (Box 234)
    - MacCormick, Austin H.
      - Report, on the Rehabilitation of Criminals, 1935 (Box 234)
    - Miller, Spencer Jr.
      - Article/essay, "Penal Progress and Prison Democracy", circa 1920 (Box 234)
    - Morris, Anna Wharton
      - Obituary, "Thomas Mott Osborne, A Great Leader," Friends' Intelligencer, LXXXIII, 1926 (Box 234)
    - Murphy, Jack
      - Article/essay, "Why Prisons Cannot Reform", circa 1913 (Box 234)
      - Book, The Fruits of Gangland (Vols. 22-24), circa 1913 (Box 234)
    - Mutual Welfare League
      - Article/essay, "Tom Brown and the Cons", 1915 (Box 234)
    - Osborne, Agnes (Devens)
      - Article/essay, On Architecture, 1887 (Box 234)
      - Diaries